Never forget why you are the church.
All right, go ahead and turn your Bibles to Revelation 12.
Revelation 12.
All right?
Last week we went over who the woman was in Revelation 12.
We're going to jump right in.
All right?
Revelation 12, verse one and two, and there appeared a great wonder in heaven,
a woman clothed with the sun and the moon under her feet, and
upon her head a crown of 12 stars.
And she, and she being with child, cried, travailing
in birth and pained to be delivered, right?
This woman, we know symbolizes Israel.
Okay?
Moon 4, we then looked at the red dragon in verses 3 and
4, and there appeared another wonder in heaven, and behold, a great
red dragon having 7 heads and 10 horns and 7 crowns upon
his heads, and his tail drew the 3rd part of the stars of
heaven, and did cast them to the earth.
And the dragon stood before the woman which was ready to be delivered, to
devour her child as soon as it was born.
Now, this is Satan, right?
The devil.
The one who has been trying to stop God's plan of redemption from
the beginning, also the one who will never and can never win.
Somebody say, amen to that.
We just sang about that, right?
We move right along to getting more details about
this child that is born of the woman.
So we're in verses 5 and 6, and she brought forth a manchild,
who was to rule all nations with a rod of iron, and her
child was caught up into God into his throne.
And the woman fled into the wilderness, where she hath a place prepared
of God, that they should feed her there 1,203
score days.
Let's pray tonight.
God, we just thank you, Lord.
We know that we're coming across some difficult text, God, of your word.
And so God, I pray you give us wisdom and discernment, God.
And also just peace and contentment when we can't know the exact
answer, God, we trust you.
Anyway, we thank you.
We love you.
In Jesus name, pray.
Amen.
Now these details that we get.
Make it crystal clear that this child is speaking of Jesus Christ.
Psalm 2 is written by King David and is
about the reign of the Lord and his anointed.
When speaking about the people devising plans
and the kings of the earth attempting to take power.
This is what he writes in Psalm chapter 2, verse 9, thou
shalt break them with a rod of iron, thou shalt dash
them in pieces like a potter's vessel.
Later in Revelation, we learn more of the victories of Jesus.
In Revelation 19, verse 15.
And out of his mouth goeth a sharp sword, that with it,
he should smite the nations, and he shall rule them with a rod of iron,
and he treaded the wine press to the fierceness and wrath of almighty God.
Now I want to make something very clear tonight.
I've talked to people, maybe you've talked to people, but
some people have a hard time connecting in their mind.
The God of the Old Testament, the Lord of hosts from the Old Testament,
and the reigning and conquering king of kings in revelation
to the meek and mild Jesus of the gospels.
There are people that literally think they would never outright come
out and say it, but they believe that it's
2 different gods.
It's 2 different persons, right?
I've literally had someone tell me, well, the God that we serve now,
Jesus is not the God of the Old Testament.
Let me just tell you something that's absolutely incorrect.
You need to understand something.
God never changes.
And if God is the same yesterday, today, and forever.
That includes all the way before the beginning of creation because
Jesus is not a created being, right?
Jesus is part of the triune God.
You had the Father, the Son, and the Holy Spirit that have always
existed in community together.
Listen, what I'm trying to say is, I cannot wrap my mind around that.
But I know it's true because God's word says so.
For example, because God is love, because
he is the prince of peace, because he is the almighty, when because
he is holy and righteous and perfect in both
character and nature, he must be wrathful
and terror inflicting on the sins of the world, it
is the only way that he can be perfect in all of his ways.
Listen, if you want a merciful God, you have one.
But you also got a wrathful and just God.
And he's the same God.
Jesus is going to reign and he will destroy
anyone who does not submit to his will.
The sad part about that is, his will is
for our good and his glory.
And so to not submit to his will is not
beneficial for us, not only today, but for eternity.
Y'all women tonight.
That's good.
I'm glad.
Thank you.
You know?
We then get to the next detail in Revelation 12, verse 5, and
she brought forth a man who was to rule all nations with a rod of iron, right?
We just talked about that language in other parts of the Bible, and
her child was caught up into God and to his throne.
This child being caught up into God and to his throne, and speaking
of the ascension of Christ Jesus.
This is not speaking here.
Some people think of speaking here, the rapture of the church.
The same word is used for caught up, right in 1st Thessalonians
for, but we know that Jesus lived, died, and
rose again, but there's even more to the gospel that we
really don't talk about enough.
He also ascended and will return.
You do realize that it's part of the gospel, not just that he lived,
that he just died, not that he rose again, but
that he ascended into heaven, and he is looking to return for his bride.
Right?
That is the gospel.
So in Acts chapter one, verse 8 through 12.
Look what he says, but ye shall receive power.
After that, the Holy Ghost has come upon you, and ye shall be witnesses unto
me both in Jerusalem.
and in all Judea, and in Samaria, and into
the uttermost parts of the earth.
And when he had spoken these things, while they beheld, he was taken
up, and a cloud received him out of their sight.
Could you imagine, 1st off, we read these things thinking, man, that's cool.
Could you imagine being there as the disciples?
Right?
None of you could imagine it?
I know, it's amazing, right?
Listen, could you imagine him literally giving you a mandate.
The person you've been following for the last three years, and then
all of a sudden, he just caught up in the clowns.
And I believe that that is a literal physical calling up
in, I don't think it's just like a, you know, they just, you know, we're
on something, and they were delirious, they salted.
No, I believe that Jesus physically ascended into heaven in the clouds.
And while they looked steadfastly toward heaven as he went up.
Behold, 2 men stood by them in wide apparel, which
also said, ye men of Galilee, why stand ye gazing up into heaven?
Think about it for a second.
They're like this right here.
Wow.
He just went up in the clouds.
Two angels come down and says, hey, guys, close your mouth, drawing flies.
Right?
You got work to do.
This same Jesus.
What is taken up from you into heaven shall so come in like manner.
And she has seen him go into heaven.
They return they unto then return they unto Jerusalem
from the mount car, all of it, which is from Jerusalem a Sabbath day's journey.
Listen, if you were there, so tonight, Master's voice, it's a Master's voice song.
I know they're frontline now, but there's a Sane saying,
and they sang it, I think, about every single time they've been here, but it's called This
Same Jesus, right?
This is the scripture where they get that from, right?
This same Jesus, the one who opened blinded eyes.
This same Jesus, the one who, the soldiers pierced his side,
this same Jesus, the one who died for my sin.
This same Jesus is gonna come back again.
That's the promise that we hold on to.
Amen?
By the way, if they don't fire you up, your wood's wet, okay?
Jesus that is thrown now, waiting the time to gather his
bride, that is the church.
If you're born again, that's you, and that's me.
Praise the Lord.
But then we get some more details here.
In Revelation 12, verse six.
And the woman fled into the wilderness where she hath a place prepared
of God, that they should feed her there a 1203 score days.
That is time frame equals to 3.5 years, or 42 months, of 30 days each.
Matthew refers to this time in Matthew 24, verse 16,
then let them which be in Judea, flee into the mountains.
That is the beginning of the great tribulation, right?
The Antichrist breaks his covenant of peace with Israel,
and things take a serious uptick in persecution, but
I need you to know that God has always protected his people, and he
will not stop now nor in the end.
Remember, this is all symbolic rather than literal here in
these particular descriptions, right?
And so this detail symbolizes the protection that God will give.
So Jesus is at his throne.
God's people are being protected.
And next we see a war break out in heaven.
Look at Revelation 12, verse 7 through 12.
And there was a war in heaven.
Michael and his angels fought against the dragon and the dragon fought and his angels.
And prevailed not, neither was their place found, and more in heaven.
And the great dragon was cast out.
That old serpent called the devil and Satan, which deceived the whole world.
He was cast out into the earth, and his angels were cast out with him.
And I heard a loud voice saying, in heaven, now has come salvation
and strength, and the kingdom of our God, and the power of his Christ,
for the accuser of our brethren, is cast
down, which accused them before our God day and night.
And they overcame him by the blood of the lamb, and by the word of their testimony,
that they love not their lives until the death.
Therefore, rejoice, ye heavens, and ye that dwell in them.
Woe to the inhabitors of the earth and of the sea, for the devil has come down unto you.
Have a great, having great wrath because he knoweth that he hath but
a short time.
Now, this right here is straight up out of a movie.
You know what I'm saying?
By the way, as I was reading that, I do want to, you know,
I do want to let you know a lot of times, if you're
like me, you see all these things that are happening
in the world, right?
Whether it be uh, international politics, whether
it be, uh, you know, American politics, whether it be something
going on locally, whether it be just like the the move
towards insanity that we see in our culture, and
we think, how in the world do people actually think like this?
Would you agree?
Have you ever thought about that?
You see somebody post something on Facebook, and you're thinking, You are, you have no brain.
I don't know even how you came up with that.
This has to be satire.
Right?
Someone say psych, you know what I'm saying?
Like, there's no way.
Let me just tell you something.
The devil right here, listen, he's deceived the whole world.
We have to understand what we're up against.
See, a lot of times we sit there and in hate and irritation
and just anger.
We lash out at these people who are simply deceived by the evil one.
You know what we need to do?
Share the gospel with them.
And hope they hope that they receive.
Listen, we cannot force them to.
I don't know who I was telling.
I think I was telling on Sunday night.
Listen, if some of these preachers that, like, slat foreheads and
do all these things and people get saved like that, you call me the forehead slapper.
I be slapping all kinds of foreheads trying to get people into heaven.
It's not how it works.
So we got to understand that this world is being deceived by the devil, right?
But we see here, Michael and his angelic army fighting Satan and his demonic army.
This is in the heavenly realm, right?
Now, the timing of this particular battle is somewhat up for debate.
Some want to put it with the first coming of Christ, right?
They would refer to when Jesus spoke to his disciples in
Luke 10, 17 through 20, and the 70 returned
again with joy saying, Lord, even the devils are subject
unto us through thy name.
By the way, I had to say this.
You know why it's so important to have the name of Jesus right there?
Because even the devil is subject to his name.
You understand what I'm saying?
There's power in the name of Jesus.
We want everyone to understand when they get in here, what we're about and who we're about.
Amen?
Okay.
And he said unto them, I beheld Satan as the lightning
fall from heaven.
Behold, I given to you the power to tread on serpents and scorpions, and over
all the power of the enemy, and nothing shall by any means hurt you.
By the way, I don't have time to preach that, but I wouldn't just go and try that right now, okay?
Understand?
There's some nuance there.
So don't just go start picking up serpents because, you know, Luke said so, okay?
Notwithstanding in this, rejoice not at the spirits or subject, and to you,
but rather rejoice because your names are written in heaven.
Now, we do not have time to go through exactly what Jesus is saying
here and the timing of this, although we do know that Jesus has
always been because Jesus is God,
so he could have been talking about any time in history, seeing Satan
fall from heaven like lightning.
But when compared to the details in Revelation 12,
there really is not enough correlation to put it,
at the first coming of Christ, this battle in heaven, this war in heaven.
This, in addition to the fact that we know that the devil has been active throughout
the church age, right?
We see this all throughout scripture, 1st Peter 58, be sober,
be vigilant, because your adversary, the devil, as a roaring
lion, walk is about, seeking whom he may devour.
I want you to know something.
We have a real enemy, and it is the devil.
He is walking around.
He is prowling around.
Sin is crouching at the door.
He's deceiving the whole world.
Listen, we don't want to underestimate him, but we don't
want to overestimate him as well.
So when we look at the text here, we can make an educated assumption
that this war happens in the end times.
So the question is, is Satan really in heaven right now?
Well, Revelation 1210, I heard a loud voice saying in heaven, now has
comes salvation and strength, and the kingdom of God, of our God
and the power of his Christ, for the accused of our brethren, is cast down, which
accused them before our God day and night.
Where's God?
I mean, he's everywhere.
Amen, but where's his tone?
In heaven, right?
So in other words, listen, for some reason,
you say, well, well, preacher, explain it, I can't.
I don't because that's not how I'd operate.
The devil would done Ben in the lick
of fire if I had the authority to do so.
But God's plans are higher and greater.
We don't, you know, so I don't want to sit here and say, um,
that I know why this happens, right?
But we see all the way back in Job's, that it Satan went to and from the
heavenly realms, right?
Joe 16.
Now, there was a day when the sons of God came to present themselves before the Lord, and
Satan came also amongst them.
Listen, you know what he's doing?
This is what he's doing.
He's coming down here.
He's seeking who he made the vour.
If you can't have your soul, he'll try to get your life here, right?
He's going up.
he's deceiving the world.
He's trying his best to get you to fight.
He's going up and he's accusing you day and night.
What a filthy little snake.
Amen?
You know what, I can't stand in school, tattletales, man.
I cannot do the kid, and you can tell a kid when they're about to tattle.
They come up with this pious looking, self righteous face, like they
really won't, you know, I got some big news for you, Mr. Jacob.
I'm like, you better tattle, ain't you?
And they'd be like, what do you mean?
I said, you better tell on somebody about something that ain't even that important.
And they'd be like, well, she did something, stop, go away.
And that's what I do.
how I handle it.
My girls, they tattle.
That's like whooping status.
Amen?
Don't be coming a tattle.
If it's something not bleeding or something not serious, do not
tattle about her stealing your blanket, steal it back.
Amen?
Don't bother me with that kind of mess.
But either way, right?
It should come to no surprise that this war takes place in heaven.
And so the devil and his demons were not strong enough,
and Michael and the angels kicked Satan out of heaven.
We then get a song of praise in Revelation 12, 10 through 11,
we said again, now has come salvation and strength, and the kingdom of our God,
and the power of his Christ, for the accused of our brethren is
cast down, which accused them before our God day and
night, and they overcame him by the blood of the Lamb, and by the word of their
testimony, and they love not their lives unto the death.
I want to say this about God accusing us day and night.
First off, some of what he's accusing us is probably true.
Because we do fall.
We do stumble.
But you know what is the vanity in him tattling on us?
is that if we know Christ, we're covered by the blood.
Amen?
It's kind of like what I said in a rough illustration.
God's like, listen, hey, that's something that's already been paid for.
You understand what I'm saying?
That's pretty cool.
But also, hey, let's try to do our best to where he has to lie about it.
You see what I'm saying?
Because he is the father of our lies.
He's gonna do whatever he can to get us to get us accused and to get us false accused.
It's exactly how they got Jesus crucified, falsely accusing him.
Right?
And so, uh, we want to make sure that we are
living a life that is glorifying to God.
That is in Revelation 12, 10 through 11.
That is the martyr's singing of victory through Jesus.
And in these verses, we see both a praise, but also a warning.
In verse 12, look at it, says, therefore rejoice, ye heavens.
And ye that dwell on them.
Woe to the inhabitors of the earth and of the sea, for the devil has
come down unto you, having great wrath, because he knoweth that he hath
but a short time.
Now, to not go too deep in this because, but
when you sit here and you think, therefore, rejoice ye heavens and ye that dwell in them,
To me, when we talk about being absent from the body and present
with the Lord, to live as Christ dies again.
I believe that as a believer, when you take your last breath, when you close your eyes in
death, you open them to see Jesus.
Okay?
So, so, I can't give you a complete explanation of that.
I just know what the Bible says about it, right?
I like how the Bible knowledge commentary explains this.
The devil knew that his time was limited to 1260 days.
The period of great tribulation.
By no stretch of the imagination can these prophecies be spread to
cover the whole interadvent age as some attempt to do so.
Right?
So, in other words, this is attached to the end time,
the great tribulation.
So what does Satan do during this time?
Well, we look at verses 13 through 14.
And when a dragon saw that he was cast out into the earth, he persecuted the
woman, which brought forth the man child.
And to the woman, we're given two wings of a great eagle, that
she might fly into the wilderness into her place, where she had nourished
for a time and time and a half a time from the face of the serpent.
Satan focuses his fury on Israel.
God protects him by bringing them to a place of security.
The wings represent a swift and powerful protection from God.
We see this same illustrative language used in Exodus 19,
talking about how God delivered them from Egypt, right?
You have seen what I did unto the Egyptians, and how I bare
you on eagle's wings and brought you unto myself.
Right?
Now, understand, I do not necessarily believe that
this woman is where everyone gets eagle's wings and flies to a place, right?
This is just talking about the symbolism of God's
protection during this time from the devil, okay?
So how protected is this woman?
Well, verses 15 and 16?
And the serpent casts out of his mouth water as a flood after the woman,
that he might cause her to be carried away of the flood.
And the earth helped the woman.
And the earth opened her mouth and swallowed up the flood, which the dragon cast out of his mouth.
Again, this is obviously all theatrical literature here to describe what is happening.
All we can know for sure is that the devil turned his focus from a heavenly
war to an earthly war, but God protects those
Satan is trying to attack.
Now, so we can't get to Israel as a whole, so Satan
now focuses even more on who he persecutes.
Look at verse 17.
And the dragon was wroth with the woman, and went to make
war with the remnant of her seed, which keep
the commandments of God and have the testimony of Jesus Christ.
Now, some think that this proves that
the woman does not represent Israel,
but rather represents the church as a whole.
Therefore, the remnant, right, is the church that's
still left or the believers that's left on the earth during this time.
Okay?
I'm not saying that necessarily can't be right.
But you also see the details that we know with the 12 stars
and all the things, you know, 1st off, the Gentiles
did not bear Jesus.
Does that make sense?
It was the Jews, right?
I'm getting ahead of myself, right?
I understand it's thought process.
However, again, Gentiles not birth Christ.
Israel did.
The line of David, specifically the tribe of Judah.
Right?
So he's definitely talking about the woman being Israel.
So then what and who is this remnant?
This remnant can still be the believers who on the earth during this time,
both Jew and Gentile alike.
Well, you say why and how?
Well, Romans 116.
For I'm not ashamed the gospel of Christ, for it is the
power of God and the salvation, everyone that believed it to the Jew 1st and
also to the Greek.
either way.
Satan is backed in a corner knowing he is defeated.
He can try, but he will not succeed in getting one
soul that God holds in his hands.
What a beautiful truth, that's not just for the tribulation end
time, but that's also for today.
And so we have to live in that victory.
See, a lot of people, a lot of people see the victory that we have in Christ as
some abstract idea for the future.
Let me just tell you something.
There's definitely victory waiting for us.
But there's also victory for us right here right now.
And so we have to live in that.
Right?
A lot of times, you know, I look back and before I
knew, you know, the whole concept of anxiety and this and
OCD and all things, you know, all the things that messes
me up and everything, you know, I remember going back
in my childhood, and I was so event driven.
If I didn't have something to look forward to, I would, I mean,
I just, I would just crumble, right?
It didn't matter if it was two weeks away, whether it was a sleepover at a friend's house,
or whether it was a get together with a youth group, whatever it was, as long as I
had something to look forward to, right?
I was good.
Now, it could have been explained that dad was traveling.
I had two sisters, one female dog, and a mama at the house, and I was also homeschooled.
Hey, man.
You know what I'm saying?
So, like, and I couldn't drive, so I was just trapped.
But either way, right?
You know, I had to look forward to something, right?
To get out of here, right?
And so, listen, sometimes Christians, if all
we're looking forward to is what is coming, we
may miss what God is doing for us right here, right now.
Now, with that being said, scripture is very clear.
We are to set our eyes on Christ.
Right?
We are to keep the hope that he is going to return.
We don't hope like the world does.
Our hope is sure, right?
Our hope is guaranteed.
It's not like I hope it happens.
I know it's going to happen, so that's my hope.
That's the biblical hope we talk about here.
But you also have to make sure that the devil is trying to
devour us today.
So therefore, we can have victory today over a defeated enemy.
Y'all with me?
What a beautiful truth.
So what hezbound eyes closed all this place before we get into our prayer time.